Ph.D. in Computer Science

8 Google Scholar

http://khoinguyen.org/

Research interests: My ultimate goal is to build a learning agent that can understand the surrounding environment in four aspects: semantic (object detection, panoptic segmentation), geometry (3D reconstruction, NeRF), dynamics (object movement, scene flow), self-localization in the environment. I am also interested in few-shot/zero-shot learning, vision-language models, and diffusion models.

EMPLOYMENT/AWARDS

Jul 2021 - Now

Research Scientist

VinAl Research

Awards

- Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, WACV 2023
- Outstanding Reviewer Award, ECCV 2020
- Vietnam Education Foundation (VEF) Fellowship (Cohort 2015)

EDUCATION

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR, USA

- Thesis: "Part-based and Uncertainty-Aware Few-shot Object Segmentation in Images"
- · Advisor: Prof. Sinisa Todorovic

Sep 2015 - Sep 2017

Master of Science in Computer Science

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR, USA

- Thesis: "Relational Networks for Visual Relationship Detection",
- · Advisor: Prof. Sinisa Todorovic

Sep 2009 - Apr 2014

Bachelors's degree in Computer Science

Bach Khoa University (HCMUT), HCMC, Vietnam

- Thesis: "Entity Disambiguation System based on Wikipedia", advisor: Prof. Tru Cao
- Top-5 student in Computer Science Program (total 330 students),

STUDENT ADVISING

Current VinAl residents

- · Nguyen Ho Quang, Feb 2023 now, **Dataset Diffusion**
- Pham Duc Hai, Feb 2023 now, Scene Understanding from Surrounding Cameras
- Luu Nguyen Hoang Minh, Feb 2023 now, NeRF for Scene Understanding
- Vu Tuan Truong, Jul 2022 now, Object Detection with Weak Labels
- Ngo Duc Tuan, Aug 2021 now, **3D Point Cloud Instance Segmentation**
- Pham Hai Chau, Aug 2021 now, Few-shot and Zero-shot Object Detection

Graduated VinAl residents

Nguyen Van Thanh, Aug 2021 - Feb 2022, Few-shot Object Counting and Detection

PUBLICATIONS

Conference papers

- · Tuan Ngo, Binh-Son Hua, Khoi Nguyen, ISBNet: a 3D Point Cloud Instance Segmentation Network with Instance-aware Sampling and Box-aware Dynamic Convolution, in Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2023
- · Hue Nguyen, Diep Tran, Khoi Nguyen, Rang Nguyen, PSENet: Progressive Self-Enhancement Network for Unsupervised Extreme-Light Image Enhancement, in Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2023, (The Best Paper - Honorable Mention Award!)
- Tuan Ngo, Khoi Nguyen, Geodesic-Former: a Geodesic-Guided Few-shot 3D Point Cloud Instance Segmenter, in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022
- Thanh Nguyen, Chau Pham, Khoi Nguyen, Minh Hoai, Few-shot Object Counting and **Detection**, in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022
- Khoi D. Nguyen, Ouoc-Huy Tran, Khoi Nguyen, Binh-Son Hua, Rang Nguyen, Inductive and Transductive Few-Shot Video Classification via Appearance and Temporal Alignments, in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022

- Khoi Nguyen, Sinisa Todorovic, iFS-RCNN: An Incremental Few-shot Instance Segmenter, in Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022
- Duong Le, Khoi D. Nguyen, Khoi Nguyen, Quoc-Huy Tran, Rang Nguyen, Binh-Son Hua, POODLE: Improving Few-shot Learning via Penalizing Out-of-Distribution Samples, in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- Khoi Nguyen, Sinisa Todorovic, **A Weakly Supervised Amodal Segmenter with Boundary Uncertainty Estimation**, in *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2021
- Khoi Nguyen, Sinisa Todorovic, FAPIS: A Few-shot Anchor-free Part-based Instance Segmenter, in Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021
- Khoi Nguyen, Sinisa Todorovic, A Self-supervised GAN for Unsupervised Few-shot
 Object Recognition, in International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR), 2020
- Khoi Nguyen, Sinisa Todorovic, Feature Weighting and Boosting for Few-Shot Segmentation, in International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019

Patents

 Khoi Nguyen, Maneesh Kumar Singh, Computer Vision Systems and Methods for Information Extraction from Text Images Using Evidence Grounding Techniques, in US Patent, 2021

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Conference Reviewer

- NeurIPS 2022
- ICLR 2022, 2023
- ICCV 2021, 2023
- CVPR 2021, 2022, 2023
- ECCV 2020, 2022

Journal Reviewer

TPAMI, TIP

EXPERIENCE

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

Research Intern

AlBee US Corp - Palo Alto, CA, USA

- Multi-person Tracking by Segmentation in Surveillance Camera
- Mentor: Dr. Chunhui Gu, Dr. Sinisa Todorovic, Dr. Silvio Savarese

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

Research Intern

Verisk Analytics - the Al Innovation Lab, Jersey City, New Jersey, USA

- Apply Graph Neural Network to image document analysis for extracting semistructured information (W2 Form)
- · Mentor: Dr. Maneesh Singh